<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pandora's box by Dan Castano</title>
    <description>Short collection of insights and thoughts.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 15:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 15:06:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empathy machine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What should we consider doing a empathy machine?. First at all, lets define empathy as the capability of understand or feel someonelse’s feelings. Some sort of machine with this functionality would be extraodinary desirable, since the main goal of every mean of communication is to send and receive messages through emiters and receptors, what could be more effective than communicate messages connected with feelings?, a new level of effective messages. For sure, everybody will work better together if we feel in the same way about several topics. I am talking about less verbal communication, less doubt about coexistence, more effectiveness, more tolerance and why not, world peace!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose we’ve already had the empathy machine. What do we want to share with other human being? We cannot simply divide the emotions that we feel in specific moments, it is too much more complicated than that. Every life event is composed by different emotions which raise or fall down according with several internal and external factors. Anyway, if we decided to communicate emotions and feelings the normal way to do it would be communicating more than one, in that order of ideas we would be communicating states (all the feelings presented in one life event).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, let’s use the most popular expression to make the exchange: “You just need to put yourself in someone else’s shoes”. Every time you use my shoe you will be able to access the life events i’ve chosen (maybe i dont want to share all my lifetime with someone else).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/empathyMachine.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;empathyMachine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this quick sketch there are some life events which worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being in jail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliver a baby&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get Married&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lose your pet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attend ITP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lose yourself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being in war.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just thing how difficult is to explain those life events to someone else, but how valuable would be if you do it correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what about if i wanna record some memorable moments, but we are not talking about photos, audio, videos of any of that. Let’s record how you felt. You put the shoe and it connects to you somehow in an Sfi mode (many things started that way). You choose your memory hole/slot and to start recording you kick the other foot slightly. You will stop recording in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our shoe will have a lifetime experience by hole and the way you decide to connect the laces and the holes will determine the storyline of the sotry you wanna communicate. On the other hand, the receptor is able to put the show and control the playback of the feelings. Does he wanna go back o go forward? It is up to him/her. Anyway, some experiences could be insufferable for some people and that’s why you can loose the tie in case of pain threshold.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/14/empathyMachine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/14/empathyMachine/</guid>
        
        
        <category>PhysicalComputation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What do you want to fake?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Baudrillard’s “procession of the simulacra” narrows down the thin line between true/false and real/imaginary. The first question is: Why do we want to make it? What is the goal behind masking the reality?. Once it is solved the following concern is: How can we fake the real world to create opinions based on rhetoric, audiovisuals and cultural bubbles?.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would I do it? As a first experimental exercise i am interested in day by day user experience. I want to know how much people are willing to believe in facts almost fictional. This thought remind me: Google Nose BETA, an April fools’ day prank made by Google on 2013 and how much people were amazed and convince about such tech advances, getting close to theirs laptop in order to catch digital smell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFbYadm_mrw&quot;&gt;Google Nose BETA (2013)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a look of these series of annual Google’s pranks, it is intriguing to find some others so much funny and others not so far of our actual tech’s capabilities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.google.com/tisp/index.html&quot;&gt;Google TiSP (2011)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It promotes free internet using the through your local municipal sewage lines. You can installed yourself (DIY). Gloves provided&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=72&amp;amp;v=Bu927_ul_X0&quot;&gt;Gmail Motion (2011)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It allows you control any gmail feature via gestures. Tracking your movements  through the laptop’s camera you were able interact in other ways without using mouse or keyboard. If you ask me, not far away from current technologies such as Microsoft Kinect or LeapMotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But those kind of products are not just a result of pranks. Some of them are sold and bought all the time between us as fake products. Products which cheat consumers selling false benefits. I am talking about product and services from shake weights, weight loss pills, weight loss wraps to false investments with high revenues, false data recovery web sites, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the same vein of thought, i’d been seduced by the idea of create a fictional product which people believe in, maybe invest in, and someday remind them how vulnerable we are to all these social media, needs, culture bubbles and fake commercials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an exercise in order to find a product: What superpower would we like to have? wanna fly? wanna read minds?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/fakingProject/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/fakingProject/</guid>
        
        
        <category>FakingTheNews</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
